Guide to the Stanford Bookstore Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford Bookstore records
1893-1994
SC0583
Stanford Bookstore.
6 Linear feet
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of the Stanford Bookstore, 1999.
Information about Access
None.
Historical Note
The Stanford Bookstore is a non-profit association that was founded in 1897 by Stanford faculty. Association membership now includes faculty, staff, and students. Seven members, two of whom must be drawn from the student membership, are elected to a board of directors that supervises the operation of the Stanford Bookstore
Scope and Content
The records of the Stanford Bookstore date from 1897 to 1994 and include minutes, correspondence, reports, financial records, leases, articles of incorporation and bylaws, contracts, and other miscellaneous items. The collection also includes one folder of records from the L.S.J.U. Co-Operative Association, 1893-1897, an earlier attempt by faculty to organize a campus bookstore. The collection is organized into the following series:
Series 1: Minutes, correspondence, and other records, 1893-78
Series 2: Business and legal records, 1897-1994
Series 3: Medical Store records, 1978-1988
Series 4: Miscellany
Access Terms
L.S.J.U. Co-Operative Association..; Booksellers and bookselling--California.; College stores.
Collection Contents
- Minutes, correspondence, and other records, 1893-1978; Series 1
  - L.S.J.U. Co-Operative Association, 1893-1897 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Stockholders, 1897-1907 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence and miscellaneous items, 1901-1907 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Annual Reports, 1902-1913 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Monthly financial reports, 1904-1905 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Secretary's Book, annual meetings, 1897-1907 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 1897-1907 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Minutes and other records, 1906-1912 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Minutes and other records, 1913-1914 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Minutes and other records, 1915-1917 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Minutes and other records, 1918-1920 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Minutes and other records, 1923-1924 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Minutes and other records, 1925-1928 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Minutes and other records, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Minutes and other records, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Minutes and other records, 1931-1932 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Minutes and other records, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Minutes and other records, 1934-1935 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Minutes and other records, 1936-1937 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Minutes and other records, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Minutes and other records, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Minutes and other records, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Minutes and other records, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Minutes and other records, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Minutes and other records, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Minutes and other records, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Minutes and other records, 1945-46 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Minutes and other records, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Minutes and other records, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Minutes and other records, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Minutes and other records, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Minutes and other records, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Minutes and other records, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Minutes and other records, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Minutes and other records, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Minutes and other records, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Minutes and other records, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Memoranda and correspondence, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Minutes and other records, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Memoranda and correspondence, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - S. U. Bookstore Survey of Comparative Prices, May 20, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Minutes and other records, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Memoranda and correspondence, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Minutes and other records, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Memoranda and correspondence, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Minutes and other records, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Memoranda and correspondence, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Minutes and other records, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Minutes and other records, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Memoranda and correspondence, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Minutes and other records, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Minutes and other records, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Minutes and other records, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Minutes and other records, 1966-1967 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Report on organizational and expansion problems, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Minutes and other records, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Annual Report, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Minutes and other records, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Year-End Report for 1969-70, Oct 28, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Minutes and other records, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Annual Report, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Minutes and other records, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Year-End Report for 1971-72, Nov 9, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Minutes and other records, 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Year-End Report for 1972-73, Nov 5, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Minutes and other records, 1973-74 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Year-End Report for, 1973-74 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Minutes and other records, 1974-1976 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous records, 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Business and legal records, 1897-1994; Series 2
  - Articles of incorporation, 1897 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Articles of incorporation and bylaws, 1947-1970 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Articles of incorporation and bylaws, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Articles of incorporation and bylaws (printed), 1902-1976 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Leases, 1905-1927 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Lease, correspondence, and extensions, 1925-1978 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Lease, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Lease amendments, 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Lease, correspondence, 1977-1994 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Santa Clara County tax records, 1907-1960 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Santa Clara County tax records, 1912-1960 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - California State tax receipts, 1916-1928 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous financial documents (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Inventory of furniture and machinery, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Architectural drawings, 1976, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Contracts: books and other publications, 1930-1942 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Contracts: miscellaneous, 1930-1953 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Contracts: Eaton Papers, 1931-1943 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Contracts: T. V. Allen, class rings, 1934-1938 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Contracts: General Electric Company (lamp division), 1934-1946 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Contracts: typewriters, 1935-1942 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Contracts: Underwood Elliott Fisher Co., 1938-1940 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Contracts: Stanford Song Book, 1940-1944 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Contracts: Royal Typewriter Company, 1941-1943 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Contracts: Class of 1945 Senior Programs (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - War Price and Rationing Board: inventory of typewriters, 1942 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Medical Store records, 1978-1988; Series 3
  - Deeds, 1978-1983 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Gift, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Purchase agreement, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Lease, 1981-1982 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Loan, Koch, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Legal papers, 1984-1988 (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Miscellany, 1951; Series 4
  - Layes, Frances: clipping re her 50 years at the Bookstore and her letter to J. Hugh Jackson, 1951 (Box 6, Folder 18)